So, what is this all about, right, the concept of SAP where it is supposed to be handling
the memory efficiently for us, but you know that would happen, that is the moment you operate
on the string, you end up creating more objects than you really require, right?
So, what is this all about?
Let's have a look at this.
So, for example, at this point, let's just assume we have Java still or Java is one still
in 2028 or let's have a different example, see, what I will do is I will have somewhere
here.
See, I will say string, well, two, for example, let's just put an idea and then you do
something with this and this developer here, right, goes for a much needed coffee break.
We know how much as developers sway lower, coffee or at least slide to post about it on
social media.
So, goes for a coffee break and in the same execution of the Jayari, a different developer
comes in, right, I told you this, SAP is there, right, this would be put in as a constraint
and string, constraint pool.
So this developer comes in and says, although well equal to IBM, right, so at this point,
what would happen is two variables would refer to the same string IBM because I told
you that's the efficient utilization.
If it's already found in the string constant pool, no new object would be created.
So, well, and otherwise, both of them would be referring to IBM because they're the same
right.
This spoke here does, otherwise has a requirement of doing that and there's for example
dot, okay, and sees is which in the space, okay, and then goes on with printed and
then goes, otherwise, obviously concatenates as well as the reassigns it, otherwise, yeah,
gets to, gets to my IBM is just wait, right, that is, would have created two more objects
in the SAP that is, is huge and IBM is huge and this one was referring to that, right.
So now, for a moment, think that strings were muted.
What would happen is this guy came up after the coffee plate and tried to print, print
it in and that said, what would he get here, that is, IBM is huge because if they were
mutable, both of them were referring to the same object, but if they were mutable, then
he would be shocked where the heck is this coming from IBM is huge because I just put
IBM doesn't know about the other program that, that is, could Kali wrote in a different
file, but in the same execution of the Java and diamond environment, so would be shocked,
shocked, and put just pinch himself to whether he's still dreaming, right, or whether he
has been working for too long, but observe that none of that is the case and that is why
they put in strings as what I told you, the constants, right, immutable.
So when this guy there is huge, this was left unchanged in the SAP, right, so that this
guy comes in, would still get IBM on screen and new object created, right.
So that is string constant pool, that is in mutability, two different concepts, but
a quite eager related, right, as you see, but still the question lies in the string constant
pool, objects are still getting by there, now we understand, alright, why did they create
SAP and why did they make strings immutable so that we don't want to have an impact somewhere
else where we don't, do not intend to, right, but objects are still getting by there,
the moment we do all these operations, right, that is where the recommendations from
Oracle comes in, first it was Sir Microsystems who was supervising the Java project,
then they sold it to Java, Java to Oracle and since around 2011, Oracle is the company
that is heading the Java project, right, it's their property thing, but we have an open
JDK as well, right, so another recommendation coming from Oracle is the first recommendation
is they say, if you have to use strings and you want to use them as read-only objects,
you don't want to tinker with them often, you don't want to change them, just use them
as read-only objects, use the Java to learn.string class, right, but your counter argument
will be, will be using strings, but we might want to change them often, right, that is
where the second recommendation from Oracle comes in, that is they say, if you have to use
strings and you want to edit, delete, update them often, do not use the string class, use
another class, that is Java dot land dot string buffer, right, right, and why did they say
so? Because with string buffer, no such concept of SCP is there, no such concept of mutability
is there, there are just normal objects which are mutable and are stored in the normal area of
RAM, and that means what does that mean, see, I just comment this for now, one of this, once
you understood this, see, what does it say is, instead of using a string, I'll say a string,
let's call it buffer, let's say string buffer, use this one, the constructor dot takes a string,
I'll say we are only eight, and then go on print buffer, and afterwards say buffer dot, now,
if you want to update the value concatenated, there's not concatenated, there's nothing,
there's the same thing takes a string, and I'll say we're moving ahead,
into advanced topics now. Okay, and I'll say a separate element buffer, what is the output that
you're expecting online number 30, is it still we are moving ahead, or is it we are moving it into
advanced topics, it was string, you just got this, it's a string buffer, you get the update
value Y, with string buffers you don't need to reassign, because the original object has been changed,
remember these are mutable, right, no, no SCT, no immutability, no changes anywhere else,
it's still we're moving ahead, and this object only was changed to be having this complete value,
that's why you get the complete value here, I'll just run this, it says you're moving ahead
into advanced topics with this line number 30, right, so that is when you want to change the string
often you want to edit it, do not use the Java to line a string class, doesn't make sense why,
because you unintentionally end up creating more objects in that Cp, right, that is when you should
use the buffer glass, but buffer has a problem, the problem is that is it's a thread safe class,
and with thread safety the performance takes ahead, what a thread safety will have a look at it
in a different medium, right, but when we were, we will be discussing multi-threading, but for now,
just think about it, that is whatever class is thread safe, it takes a performance it, that's why
the third recommendation for miracle comes in, and that's the best recommendation,
and that is they say if you have to use strings and you want to edit them often,
right, and performance isn't right here, then go ahead and use the Java to line dot string builder
class, and this class was a new addition to the language in Java 5, right, it's again a new
Java 5 addition, they say again a class in the Java to line package, that is string builder,
again I'll just repeat it for you, when you want to use strings, and you want to edit them
as you want, as you required, and performance is a concern, use the number one recommended class
for miracle, that is Java to line dot string builder, and string builder and string buffer are the
same except buffer is a thread safe class, string builder is not, that's why the performance is high
when you're using string builder, and you get mutability, and no such concept as CPC, it's the same
except that it is not thread safe, that's it, see, all other things are the same, I'll just call it
value or value for now, or let's put it over, it doesn't matter, see, but just string builder,
you'll still get the same outcome because no such concept of a CPC, same as string buffer,
no immutability, same as buffer, they differ with string, right, but string builder is the
fastest class in Java, so now you know why I said it's a comprehensive API with strings, you have
three classes in the API right string, for a different purpose, string buffer and builder,
for different purposes only to be there.